Finding Aid for the Horace Marden Albright Papers LSC.2056
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Correspondence: Arranged by Agency
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous photographs. (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence., 1918-1930 (Box 51-52)
- Printed Material: Arranged by Parks
  - Acadia. (Box 53)
  - Acadia; Alaska. (Box 54)
  - Blue Ridge. (Box 55)
  - California National Parks. (Box 56)
  - California State Parks. (Box 57)
  - Carlsbad Caverns. (Box 58)
  - Colonial National Park. (Box 59)
  - Colonial National Park, visit by Queen Elizabeth II, mainly newspapers., 1957 (Box 60)
  - Colonial National Park, also Jamestown and Yorktown. (Box 61)
  - Crater Lake (Box 62)
  - Death Valley. (Box 63-67)
  - Death Valley Moss Hearings. (Box 68)
  - Dinosaur. (Box 69)
  - Glacier. (Box 70)
  - Grand Canyon. (Box 71)
  - Grand Tetons. (Box 72-74)
  - Great Smoky Mountains. (Box 75)
  - Mesa Verde. (Box 76)
  - Mount Rainier. (Box 77)
  - National Capital Parks. (Box 78)
  - New York State Parks. (Box 79)
  - Olympia. (Box 80)
  - Rocky Mountain. (Box 81)
  - Sagamore Hill. (Box 82)
  - Redwoods. (Box 83-85)
  - Sequoia-Kings Canyon (general grant). (Box 86)
- Yellowstone
  - Trail Guides to Yellowstone National Park. (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - Geysers in Yellowstone National Park. (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous publications on Yellowstone National Park. (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - Journal articles on Yellowstone National Park. (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - Bechler River news clippings., 1923-1928 (Box 87, Folder 5-6)
  - National Trout Derby, Livingston, Montana., 1957 (Box 87, Folder 7)
  - News clippings., 1923-1928 (Box 87, Folder 8)
  - News clippings. (Box 87, Folder 9)
  - The Savage - Yellowstone National Park area paper. (Box 87, Folder 10)
  - Annual reports on Yellowstone National Park by Chief of Engineers, 1887-1903 (Box 88, Folder 1-2)
    - 1899-1902. (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - 1887-88, 1890-91, 1903. (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - Yellowstone National Park Guides. U.S. Department of the Interior., 1919, 1926, 1928, 1929 (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - Guides to Yellowstone National Park. (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - U.S. Government publications on Yellowstone National Park. (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Department of Interior publications on Yellowstone National Park. (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - Congressional publications on Yellowstone National Park. (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - Maps of Yellowstone National Park. (Box 88, Folder 8)
  - Reports on Yellowstone National Park to Secretary of the Interior., 1895-1898 (Box 88, Folder 9)
  - Wildlife Management on National Parks, National Park Service., 1962-1963 (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - Yellowstone National Park Master Plan Study. Management Programs (Box 89, Folder 2-5)
    - South District. (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - West District. (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - North District. (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Park General. (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Park organization., 1964 (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - Estimates and justification for Yellowstone National Park fiscal., 1928 (Box 89, Folder 7)
  - "The Bison of Yellowstone National Park"--article by HMA. (Box 89, Folder 8)
  - Yellowstone Information Manual, vol.1 (Fauna)., 1930 (Box 89, Folder 9)
  - "The Birth of Yellowstone National Park" play by Bert Hansen., 1957 (Box 89, Folder 10)
  - Hot spring activity in the geyser basins of the Firehole River for the season., 1959 (Box 89, Folder 11)
  - National Park Service Annual Report., 1938-1943 (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Yellowstone National Park attendance figures., 1926, 1939, 1943 (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Animal stocks in Yellowstone National Park., 1940s (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - HMA correspondence with Department of the Interior over Yellowstone National Park finances., 1924 (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Report on Permanent Educational Improvements at Upper Basin Yellowstone National Park Made in 1926 Season. (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - Yellowstone Interpretive News. (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - Native notes from Yellowstone National Park. (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous papers on Geysers. (Box 90, Folder 8)
  - Preliminary papers on Geology of Yellowstone National Park. Department of the Interior., 1955 (Box 90, Folder 9)
  - Manual of Park Operations., 1964[?] (Box 90, Folder 10)
  - Proposal to dam Yellowstone Lake., 1938 (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - Yellowstone National Park press releases, Department of Interior. (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous articles on Yellowstone National Park. (Box 91, Folder 3-4, 6-7)
  - Newspaper clippings. (Box 91, Folder 5)
  - Congressional printed papers about Yellowstone National Park. (Box 91, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Yellowstone National Park papers. (Box 91, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Yellowstone National Park photographs. (Box 91, Folder 10)
  - 3 photos of Horace M. Albright Visitor Center, Yellowstone National Park., March 1985 (Box 91, Folder 11)
  - Ranger Naturalists Manual of Yellowstone National Park. (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - Printed papers on Yellowstone. (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - Montana Banker., September 1928 (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - Mammoth [?]. (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - Wildlife in Yellowstone National Park. (Box 92, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous publications on Yellowstone National Park. (Box 92, Folder 6)
  - National Park Service Yosemite news releases. (Box 92, Folder 7)
  - Yellowstone Weekday News. (Box 92, Folder 8)
  - Unprocessed. Mainly printed papers, correspondence with conservation groups. (Box 93-95)
  - Yosemite. (Box 96-98)
- National Park Service Areas: A - G
  - Abraham Lincoln Birthplace. (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Adams Mansion - Massachusetts. (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Alaskan National Parks. (Box 99, Folder 3-5)
  - Antietam National Battlefield Site Maryland. (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - Appalachian Trailway. (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - Assateaque Island, Virginia. (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - Aztec Ruins National Monument, New Mexico. (Box 99, Folder 9)
  - Badlands National Monument, South Dakota. (Box 99, Folder 10)
  - Bandelier National Monument, New Mexico. (Box 99, Folder 11)
  - Big Bend National Park, Texas. (Box 99, Folder 12)
  - Black Canyon of the Gunnison National Monument, Colorado. (Box 99, Folder 13)
  - Blue Ridge Parkway, Virginia/North Carolina. (Box 99, Folder 14)
  - Brice's Crossroads National Battlefield Site, Tupelo, Michigan. (Box 99, Folder 15)
  - Bryce Canyon National Park, Utah. (Box 99, Folder 16)
  - Buffalo National River, Arizona. (Box 99, Folder 17)
  - Cabrillo National Monument, California. (Box 99, Folder 18)
  - Canyon de Chelly National Monument, Arizona. (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - Canyonlands National Park, Utah. (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - Capulin Mountain National Park, Utah. (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - Casa Grande National Monument, Arizona. (Box 100, Folder 4)
  - Castillo de San Marcos, St. Augustine, Florida. (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - Castle Clinton National Monument, New York. (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - Cholmette Historical Park, Louisiana. (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - Channel Islands National Monument, California. (Box 100, Folder 8)
  - Crater Lake National Park, Oregon. (Box 100, Folder 9)
  - Cumberland Gap National Historical Park, Kentucky, Texas, Virginia. (Box 100, Folder 10)
  - Devil's Tower National Monument, Wyoming. (Box 100, Folder 11)
  - Dinosaur National Monument, Utah. (Box 100, Folder 12-13)
  - Edison Laboratory National Monument, New Jersey. (Box 100, Folder 14)
  - Escalante Canyon, Utah. (Box 100, Folder 15)
  - Everglades National Park, Florida. (Box 100, Folder 16)
  - Federal Hall Memorial, New York. (Box 100, Folder 17)
  - Fire Island National Park, New York. (Box 100, Folder 18)
  - Florida Coral Reefs. (Box 100, Folder 19)
  - Fort Bowie National Historic Site, Arizona. (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - Fort Jefferson National Monument, Florida. (Box 101, Folder 2)
  - Fort Laramie National Historic Site, Wyoming. (Box 101, Folder 3)
  - Fort Necessity National Battlefield Site, Pennsylvania. (Box 101, Folder 4)
  - Fort Raleigh National Historical Site, North Carolina. (Box 101, Folder 5)
  - Fort Union National Monument, New Mexico. (Box 101, Folder 6)
  - George Washington Birthplace National Monument, Virginia. (Box 101, Folder 7)
  - Gettysburg National Military Park, Pennsylvania. (Box 101, Folder 8)
  - Glacier National Park, Montana. (Box 101, Folder 9-10)
  - Glacier Bay National Monument, Alabama. (Box 101, Folder 11)
  - Glen Canyon Damsite, Company. (Box 101, Folder 12)
  - Golden Spike National Monument, Utah. (Box 101, Folder 13)
  - Gran Quivira National Monument, New Mexico. (Box 101, Folder 14)
  - Grand Canyon, Arizona. (Box 101, Folder 15-17)
  - Great Smoky Mountains National Park. (Box 101, Folder 18)
- National Park Service Areas, H - Z
  - Hamilton Grange, New York. (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - Harper's Ferry, Virginia. (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - Hawaiian National Parks. (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - Herbert Hoover Presidential Library, Cedar Rapids, Iowa. (Box 102, Folder 4)
  - Home of Franklin D. Roosevelt, Hyde Park, New York. (Box 102, Folder 5)
  - Hopwell Village National Historical Site, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. (Box 102, Folder 6)
  - Independence National Historical Site, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. (Box 102, Folder 7)
  - Isle Royale National Park, Michigan. (Box 102, Folder 8)
  - Jefferson National Expansion Monument, St. Louis, Missouri. (Box 102, Folder 9)
  - Joshua Tree National Monument, California. (Box 102, Folder 10)
  - King's Mountain National Military Park, South Carolina (Box 102, Folder 11)
  - Lake Mead, Lake Mojave, and the Colorado River, Arizona/Nevada. (Box 102, Folder 12)
  - Lassen Volcanic National Park, Mineral, California. (Box 102, Folder 13)
  - Lava Beds National Monument, California. (Box 102, Folder 14)
  - Lyndon B. Johnson Library, Texas. (Box 102, Folder 15)
  - Livingston, Montana: Yellowstone National Park. (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - Mammoth Cave National Park, Kentucky. (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Manassas National Battlefield Park, Virgnia. (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - Mesa Verde National Park, Company. (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - Morristown National HIstorical Park, New York. (Box 103, Folder 5)
  - Mound City Group National Monument, Ohio. (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - Mount McKinley National Park, Alaska. (Box 103, Folder 7)
  - Mount Rainier National Park, Washington. (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - [?] Trace Parkway, Mississippi, Alabama, Tennessee. (Box 103, Folder 9)
  - Navajo Canyon and Mountain, Utah. (Box 103, Folder 10)
  - North Cascade Mountains, Washington. (Box 103, Folder 11)
  - Olympic National Park, Washington. (Box 103, Folder 12)
  - Ocmulgee National Monument, Georgia. (Box 103, Folder 13)
  - Petrified Forest National Monument, Arizona. (Box 103, Folder 14)
  - Pipe Spring National Monument, Arizona. (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - Point Reyes, California. (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - Rainbow Bridge National Monument, Utah (1). (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - Rainbow Bridge National Monument, Utah (2) - Valley Monument Expedition. (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - Rainbow Bridge National Monument, Utah (3). (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - Redwoods National Park, California. (Box 104, Folder 6-7)
  - Rocky Mountains National Park. (Box 105, Folder 1-2)
  - Richmond National Battlefield Park, Virginia. (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - Sagamore Hill National Historic Site, New York. (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - Saguaro National Monument, Arizona. (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - Saint Paul's Church, Eastchester, Mt. Vernon, New York. (Box 105, Folder 6)
  - Salem Maritime National Historic Site, Maryland. (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - Saratoga National Historical Park, New York. (Box 105, Folder 8)
  - Sawtooth National Park, Idaho. (Box 105, Folder 9)
  - Scott's Bluff National Monument, Nevada. (Box 105, Folder 10)
  - Shenandoah National Park, Virginia. (Box 105, Folder 11)
  - South Dakota - Custer State Park. (Box 105, Folder 12)
  - Southern Appalachian Mountain National Parks, Virginia. (Box 105, Folder 13)
  - Statue of Liberty - American Museum of Immigration. (Box 106, Folder 1-2)
  - Sunset Crater National Monument, Arizona. (Box 106, Folder 3)
  - Theodore Roosevelt National Memorial Park, North Dakota. (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - Tumacocovi, Arizona. (Box 106, Folder 5)
  - Vanderbilt Mansion National Historic Site; Hyde Park, New York. (Box 106, Folder 6)
  - Vicksburg National Military Park, Mississippi. (Box 106, Folder 7)
  - Virgin Islands National Parks. (Box 106, Folder 8)
  - Voyageurs National Park, Minnesota. (Box 106, Folder 9)
  - White Sands National Monument, New Mexico. (Box 106, Folder 10)
  - Zion National Park, Utah. (Box 106, Folder 11)
- State Parks
  - Including Elysian Park, and Fort Massac. (Box 111)
  - Including Fort Massac and Big Sur. (Box 112)
  - National Parks and Monuments. (Box 113-118)
  - Proposed National and State Parks. (Box 119)
  - Canadian National Parks. (Box 120)
  - Foreign Parks, including Canada, Mexico, Turkey, and Great Britain. (Box 121-122)
  - Far Eastern National Parks, including Taiwan, Hong Kong, Korea, and Micronesia. (Box 123)
  - African National Parks, especially Belgian Congo. (Box 124)
- [Arranged By] Agency
  - National Park Service
    - Correspondence., 1940s and 1950s (Box 125)
    - Policy Statements. (Box 126-127)
    - Service History. (Box 128)
    - Concessions. (Box 129-130)
    - Concessionaires. (Box 131)
    - Land Matters. (Box 132)
    - Advisory Board on National Parks, Historic Sites, Buildings and Monuments. (Box 133-135)
    - Annual Reports; Directors and Engineers. (Box 136)
    - Congressional Appropriations for National Park Service. (Box 137)
    - Congressional Records of National Park Service legislation., 1932 (Box 138)
      Also correspondence, 1929.
    - Legislative program for National Park Service., 1929-1931 (Box 139)
    - Legislative program for National Park Service, 1929-1931 (Box 140)
      Also National Park Service Handbook of Energy Conservation Work.
    - Congressional Records of National Park Service legislation., 1928-1929 (Box 141)
    - Mission 66. (Box 142)
    - Park conferences. (Box 143)
  - National Park Service Publications
    - Weekly Reports to Secretary., 1964 (Box 144, Folder 1)
    - Weekly Reports to Secretary., 1965 (Box 144, Folder 2)
    - Professional Rangers Organization Newsletter., May 1971 (Box 144, Folder 3)
    - Southwestern Monuments Reports., 1933, 1943-44 (Box 144, Folder 4)
    - Director's Staff Meetings, 1956-1971 (Box 144, Folder 5-9)
      - July 1956-May 1959. (Box 144, Folder 5)
      - June-October 1959. (Box 144, Folder 6)
      - November 1959-November 1960. (Box 144, Folder 7)
      - June 1961-July 1964. (Box 144, Folder 8)
      - October 1966-February 1971. (Box 144, Folder 9)
    - Staff Meeting Minutes - Region Four. (Box 144, Folder 10)
    - Staff Meeting Minutes - Regional. (Box 144, Folder 11)
    - Park Service News., January 1920-August 1921 (Box 144, Folder 12)
    - Park Service Bulletin., March 1922-January 1930 (Box 144, Folder 13)
    - Park Service Bulletin., August 1945-August 1953 (Box 145, Folder 1)
    - National Park Service Newsletter., 1967-1969 (Box 145, Folder 2)
    - National Park Service Newsletter., 1970-1974 (Box 145, Folder 3)
    - National Park Courier, 1957-1974 (Box 145-147)
      - 1957-1959. (Box 145, Folder 4)
      - 1960-1961. (Box 145, Folder 5)
      - 1962. (Box 145, Folder 6)
      - 1963. (Box 145, Folder 7)
      - 1964. (Box 146, Folder 1)
      - 1965. (Box 146, Folder 2)
      - 1966. (Box 146, Folder 3)
      - 1967. (Box 146, Folder 4)
      - January-April 1968. (Box 146, Folder 5)
      - May-December 1968. (Box 146, Folder 6)
      - 1969. (Box 147, Folder 1)
      - 1970. (Box 147, Folder 2)
      - 1971. (Box 147, Folder 3)
      - 1972. (Box 147, Folder 4)
      - 1973. (Box 147, Folder 5)
      - 1974. (Box 147, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous papers. (Box 148-149)
    - Miscellaneous National Park Service reports. (Box 150)
  - Other Agencies
    - American Conservation Association. (Box 151)
    - Christian Ministry in the National Parks. (Box 152)
    - Colonial Williamsburg. (Box 153-157)
      Some correspondence in Box 156.
    - Committee for the Preservation of the Tule Elk. (Box 158)
      (50% correspondence)
    - J.N. "Ding" Darling Foundation. (Box 159)
    - Jackson Hole Preserve. (Box 160-162)
      Mainly correspondence in Box 162.
    - Joint Civilian Orientation Conference. (Box 163)
    - National Parks Association. (Box 164)
    - National Resources Planning Board; Pecos River Report; National Planning Board Report., 1933-34 (Box 165)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation (formerly National Council for Historic Sites and Buildings); some correspondence. (Box 166-167)
    - ORRRC: Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission. (Box 168)
    - Palisades Interstate Park Commission. (Box 169-170)
    - Resources for Freedom. (Box 171-172)
    - Resources for the Future - meetings, annual reports. (Box 173-178)
    - Save the Redwoods League. (Box 179-183)
    - Correspondence, 1920-1973 (Box 179-181)
      - 1920-1921, 1928, 1931, 1944. (Box 179, Folder 1)
      - 1946-1949. (Box 179, Folder 2)
      - 1950-1951. (Box 179, Folder 3)
      - 1952. (Box 179, Folder 4)
      - 1953-1955. (Box 179, Folder 5)
      - 1956-1959. (Box 179, Folder 6)
      - May-December 1963. (Box 180, Folder 1)
      - January-June 1964. (Box 180, Folder 2)
      - July-October 1964. (Box 180, Folder 3)
      - November-December 1964. (Box 180, Folder 4)
      - January-March 1965. (Box 180, Folder 5)
      - April-May 1965. (Box 180, Folder 6)
      - June-September 1965. (Box 180, Folder 7)
      - October-December 1965. (Box 180, Folder 8)
      - January-February 1966. (Box 180, Folder 9)
      - March 1966. (Box 181, Folder 1)
      - April-December 1966; March 1967. (Box 181, Folder 2)
      - January-September 1968. (Box 181, Folder 3)
      - October-December 1968. (Box 181, Folder 4)
      - 1969. (Box 181, Folder 5)
      - 1970. (Box 181, Folder 6)
      - 1971. (Box 181, Folder 7)
      - 1972-1973. (Box 181, Folder 8)
    - Internal Memoranda to Board of Governors, 1966-1973 (Box 181, Folder 9-10)
      - 1966-1971. (Box 181, Folder 9)
      - 1965-1971, 1973. (Box 181, Folder 10)
    - Board of Councillors, minutes of annual meetings. (Box 181, Folder 11)
    - Press Releases., 1964-1971 (Box 181, Folder 12)
    - Save the Redwoods League Bulletin., 1941-1972 (Box 181, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous papers. (Box 182, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous statistical papers. (Box 182, Folder 2)
    - History, rules, regulations. (Box 182, Folder 3)
    - Mailings to members. (Box 182, Folder 4)
    - Publications. (Box 182, Folder 5-6)
    - News clippings about Redwoods., pre-1966 (Box 182, Folder 7)
    - News clippings about Redwoods., 1966-1971 (Box 182, Folder 8)
    - News clippings., 1966-1971; (Photocopies) (Box 182, Folder 9)
    - Press releases concerning Redwoods. (Box 182, Folder 10)
    - U.S. and state bills concerning Redwoods. (Box 182, Folder 11)
    - Photographs of Redwood trees. (Box 182, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous papers concerning Redwoods. (Box 183, Folder 1)
    - Publications, postcards, pamphlets on Redwoods. (Box 183, Folder 2)
    - Reprinted newspaper and magazine articles on Redwoods. (Box 183, Folder 3)
    - Magazine articles on Redwoods. (Box 183, Folder 4)
    - Sierra Club papers concerning Redwoods. (Box 183, Folder 5)
    - Our Public Land - Bureau of Land Management., 1961; (4 issues) (Box 183, Folder 6)
    - Maps covering Redwood areas. (Box 183, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous printed papers. (Box 183, Folder 8-9)
    - National Park Service file on Ralph Pritchett; mainly correspondence with Newton P. Drury., 1939-1948 (Box 183, Folder 10)
    - South Calaveras Grove (unprocessed). (Box 184)
    - Save the Redwoods League. (Box 185-187)
    - U.S. Geological Survey. (Box 188)
- [Arranged By] Subject
  - Conservation. (Box 189-191)
  - Elk. (Box 192)
  - Elk - Yellowstone. (Box 193)
  - Environment. (Box 194)
  - Environmental Planning. (Box 195)
  - Forestry. (Box 196)
  - Forest Preservation. (Box 197)
  - Grazing. (Box 198)
  - Mining. (Box 199)
  - Natural Resources. (Box 200)
  - Outdoor Recreation. (Box 201-202)
  - Population Growth and Urbanization. (Box 203-204)
  - Roads. (Box 205)
  - Student Conservation. (Box 206)
  - Water Resources. (Box 207-208)
  - Wilderness. (Box 209)
  - Wilderness., 1958 and n.d. (Box 210)
    Includes 1958 hearings on National Wilderness Preservation Act.
  - Wildlife (including bison). (Box 211-213)
  - Wildlife (including fish). (Box 214)
  - Wildlife. (Box 215)
- Biographical
  - General. (Box 216-217)
  - Retirement letters. (Box 218)
- Items Collected During Travels
  [Mainly printed brochures and maps]
  - United States. (Box 219-221)
  - England. (Box 222)
  - Great Britain. (Box 223)
  - Canada. (Box 224)
  - Netherlands. (Box 225)
  - Germany. (Box 226)
  - France. (Box 227)
  - Germany, France. (Box 228)
  - Europe. (Box 229-230)
- Magazines, Bulletins, Printed Materials
  - News and Views - State of California, Division of Beaches and Parks. (Box 231)
  - Miscellaneous periodicals, including: (Box 232-239)
    Sierra Club Bulletin
    Desert
    Center Report
    American Forests
    National Wildlife
    Wildlife News
    Parks and Recreation
    Smithsonian
    American Heritage
    The Argonaut
    William and Mary Quarterly (239)
    Bulletin of the Pacific Tropical Botanical Garden
    Defenders of Wildlife News
    20 Mule Team Magazine
    Southern Sierra
    Environment
    News and Views
    New Mexico
    Holiday
    The Conservationist
    Westways
    International Wildlife
  - Sierra Club Bulletin. (Box 240)
  - Miscellaneous printed material, periodicals, and conservation group newsletters. (Box 241-243)
- Horace M. Albright Lectures
  - Horace M. Albright Lectures. (Box 244)
- Miscellaneous Subjects (in no Particular Order)
  - Correspondence with Arthur Carhart, Amelia Fry UCLA and Denver Libraries. (Box 245)
  - Harold L. Ickes. (Box 246-247)
  - U.S. Department of the Interior - Oscar L. Chapman and Stewart Udall. (Box 248)
    Mainly news clippings, some correspondence.
  - Advisory Board - Knopf and Laurence Rockefeller. (Box 249)
    Mainly correspondence.
  - National Capital. (Box 250)
  - Theodore Roosevelt Island correspondence. (Box 250)
  - Santa Monica Mountains study. (Box 251)
    Some correspondence.
  - Preservation of the Past. (Box 252)
  - University of California. (Box 253)
  - Historic Preservation. (Box 254)
  - History. (Box 255)
  - Nature Education. (Box 256)
  - Nature Guides to the Southwest U.S. (Box 256)
  - Biographies. (Box 257)
  - Early Publicity. (Box 258)
  - Forestry. (Box 258)
  - Book catalogues. (Box 259)
  - Inyo County. (Box 260)
    Mainly news clippings.
  - American Indians. (Box 261)
  - Directories for National Park Service, Cosmos Club, Explorer's Club, National Wildlife Federation, National Trust for Historical Preservation. (Box 262)
  - U.S. Budget. (Box 263)
  - Government reorganization of departments., 1932 (Box 264)
  - Hoover Commission. (Box 265-268)
  - Miscellaneous printed papers; book announcements. (Box 269)
- Files on Various Topics
  - Architecture in the National Parks. (Box 270, Folder 1)
  - Caves. (Box 270, Folder 2)
  - Chamber of Commerce of the U.S.A. (Box 270, Folder 3)
  - Clubs: Century Club. (Box 270, Folder 4)
  - Colleges or Universities. (Box 270, Folder 5)
  - Conservation, general. (Box 270, Folder 6)
  - Indians. (Box 270, Folder 7)
  - Joint Civilian Orientation Conference, Department of Defense. (Box 270, Folder 8)
  - MacAlester College, St. Paul, Minnesota. (Box 270, Folder 9)
  - Madison River, Montana. (Box 270, Folder 10)
  - Mills College, Oakland, California. (Box 271, Folder 1)
  - Montana School of Mines. (Box 271, Folder 2)
  - Mount San Jacinto Tramway. (Box 271, Folder 3)
  - Mount Woodring, Grand Teton National Park. (Box 271, Folder 4)